<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>tech.dongdongbh.mindwtr</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>AGPL-3.0-only</project_license>
  <name>Mindwtr</name>
  <summary>Plan tasks and projects</summary>
  <developer id="tech.dongdongbh">
    <name>Dongda Li</name>
  </developer>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">tech.dongdongbh.mindwtr.desktop</launchable>
  <provides>
    <binary>mindwtr</binary>
  </provides>
  <description>
    <p>Capture tasks, organize projects, and keep work moving with a simple personal system that keeps your data on your device.</p>
    <p>Mindwtr helps you sort inbox items, review commitments, and plan next actions without requiring an account or locking you into a proprietary service.</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Capture tasks, notes, and ideas quickly</li>
      <li>Organize work with projects, areas, sections, tags, and contexts</li>
      <li>Review your lists daily or weekly to stay current</li>
      <li>Plan with list, board, and calendar views</li>
      <li>Add notes, reminders, and attachments to your work</li>
      <li>Sync through local folders, WebDAV, Dropbox, or a self-hosted cloud</li>
    </ul>
  </description>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default" xml:lang="en">
      <caption>Review tasks across your lists</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dongdongbh/Mindwtr/main/apps/desktop/screenshots/review_light.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot xml:lang="en">
      <caption>Capture tasks quickly in Inbox</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dongdongbh/Mindwtr/main/apps/desktop/screenshots/inbox_light.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot xml:lang="en">
      <caption>Learn the workflow with the built-in guide</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dongdongbh/Mindwtr/main/apps/desktop/screenshots/tutorial_light.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <branding>
    <color type="primary" scheme_preference="light">#6AB8FF</color>
    <color type="primary" scheme_preference="dark">#3341A5</color>
  </branding>
  <categories>
    <category>Office</category>
    <category>Utility</category>
  </categories>
  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/dongdongbh/Mindwtr</url>
  <url type="donation">https://ko-fi.com/dongdongbh</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/dongdongbh/Mindwtr/issues</url>
  <url type="vcs-browser">https://github.com/dongdongbh/Mindwtr</url>
  <releases>
    <release version="0.7.5" date="2026-03-18">
      <url type="details">https://github.com/dongdongbh/Mindwtr/releases/tag/v0.7.5</url>
      <description translate="no">
        <p>Mindwtr 0.7.5 improves desktop deletion flows, settings stability, sync resilience, and Linux packaging polish.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Added confirmation and undo for list deletions, with clearer feedback when restores fail.</li>
          <li>Stabilized the Integrations settings screen and blocked checklist edits on reference-only items.</li>
          <li>Improved sync resilience with safer pending writes, task mutation validation, and better self-write filtering.</li>
          <li>Expanded Linux packaging metadata with AppStream polish and automated Flathub follow-up updates.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.7.4" date="2026-03-16">
      <url type="details">https://github.com/dongdongbh/Mindwtr/releases/tag/v0.7.4</url>
      <description translate="no">
        <p>Mindwtr 0.7.4 adds Apple-platform iCloud sync, a desktop Obsidian workspace, stronger cross-device sync reliability, and faster mobile triage tools.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Added native iCloud sync support on Apple platforms.</li>
          <li>Added Obsidian vault integration on desktop with a dedicated workspace that stays hidden until enabled.</li>
          <li>Improved sync reliability with safer merge handling, bounded cloud requests, and clearer conflict diagnostics.</li>
          <li>Added a global mobile area switcher, time estimate filters, and daily-review focus toggles.</li>
          <li>Improved desktop layouts, sync accessibility, and release tooling for the Node 24 transition.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.7.3" date="2026-03-05">
      <url type="details">https://github.com/dongdongbh/Mindwtr/releases/tag/v0.7.3</url>
      <description translate="no">
        <p>Mindwtr 0.7.3 focused on more consistent sync behavior, safer local persistence, more workflow customization, and better mobile reminder handling.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Unified desktop and mobile sync orchestration to reduce stale queued-sync edge cases.</li>
          <li>Added date and time format overrides and opt-in inbox processing settings on desktop.</li>
          <li>Added a visible mobile sync activity indicator and improved WebDAV rate-limit handling.</li>
          <li>Hardened local storage, search, attachment validation, and self-hosted cloud merge behavior.</li>
          <li>Improved notification reliability, task editing flows, and calendar permission handling.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1"/>
</component>
