<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>tech.dongdongbh.mindwtr</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>AGPL-3.0-only</project_license>
  <name>Mindwtr</name>
  <summary>Plan tasks and projects</summary>
  <developer id="tech.dongdongbh">
    <name>Dongda Li</name>
  </developer>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">tech.dongdongbh.mindwtr.desktop</launchable>
  <provides>
    <binary>mindwtr</binary>
  </provides>
  <description>
    <p>Capture tasks, organize projects, and keep work moving with a simple personal system that keeps your data on your device.</p>
    <p>Mindwtr helps you sort inbox items, review commitments, and plan next actions without requiring an account or locking you into a proprietary service.</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Capture tasks, notes, and ideas quickly</li>
      <li>Organize work with projects, areas, sections, tags, and contexts</li>
      <li>Review your lists daily or weekly to stay current</li>
      <li>Plan with list, board, and calendar views</li>
      <li>Add notes, reminders, and attachments to your work</li>
      <li>Sync through local folders, WebDAV, Dropbox, or a self-hosted cloud</li>
    </ul>
  </description>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default" xml:lang="en">
      <caption>Review tasks across your lists</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dongdongbh/Mindwtr/main/apps/desktop/screenshots/review_light.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot xml:lang="en">
      <caption>Capture tasks quickly in Inbox</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dongdongbh/Mindwtr/main/apps/desktop/screenshots/inbox_light.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot xml:lang="en">
      <caption>Learn the workflow with the built-in guide</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dongdongbh/Mindwtr/main/apps/desktop/screenshots/tutorial_light.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <branding>
    <color type="primary" scheme_preference="light">#6AB8FF</color>
    <color type="primary" scheme_preference="dark">#3341A5</color>
  </branding>
  <categories>
    <category>Office</category>
    <category>Utility</category>
  </categories>
  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/dongdongbh/Mindwtr</url>
  <url type="donation">https://ko-fi.com/dongdongbh</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/dongdongbh/Mindwtr/issues</url>
  <url type="vcs-browser">https://github.com/dongdongbh/Mindwtr</url>
  <releases>
    <release version="0.8.5" date="2026-04-19">
      <url type="details">https://github.com/dongdongbh/Mindwtr/releases/tag/v0.8.5</url>
      <description translate="no">
        <p>Mindwtr 0.8.5 sharpens desktop review and project planning while tightening attachment and sync behavior for Linux desktop users.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Added review sort and detail controls plus a resizable projects sidebar with steadier width syncing.</li>
          <li>Let the projects workspace use more width and improved task editing with inline image previews and undo support.</li>
          <li>Improved desktop attachment-path handling and re-enabled CloudKit autosync on desktop builds.</li>
          <li>Preferred the web audio backend on Flatpak and updated Flathub-facing release plumbing.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.8.4" date="2026-04-16">
      <url type="details">https://github.com/dongdongbh/Mindwtr/releases/tag/v0.8.4</url>
      <description translate="no">
        <p>Mindwtr 0.8.4 is a maintenance release focused on sync documentation and regression coverage for desktop builds.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Documented the SQLite-to-JSON bridge so the local-store and sync-snapshot contract is easier to reason about.</li>
          <li>Clarified the current sync behavior and roadmap wording in the main docs.</li>
          <li>Added regression coverage to ensure device-local sync history does not trigger unnecessary remote writes.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.8.3" date="2026-04-14">
      <url type="details">https://github.com/dongdongbh/Mindwtr/releases/tag/v0.8.3</url>
      <description translate="no">
        <p>Mindwtr 0.8.3 expands desktop planning and Markdown editing while tightening Linux-facing polish and sync recovery.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Expanded desktop Markdown notes with fullscreen editors, toolbar actions, automatic list continuation, and task/project internal links.</li>
          <li>Added area filter keyboard chords, task-date clear buttons, contexts bulk energy assignment, and a new energy-level focus filter.</li>
          <li>Kept the desktop shell tidier with persistent collapsible sidebar sections, localized native date inputs, Lucide sync-setting icons, and remembered area collapse state.</li>
          <li>Made sync recovery safer by preserving recoverable createdAt timestamps and flushing pending writes before retry recovery.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.8.2" date="2026-04-11">
      <url type="details">https://github.com/dongdongbh/Mindwtr/releases/tag/v0.8.2</url>
      <description translate="no">
        <p>Mindwtr 0.8.2 sharpens desktop capture, error handling, and sync recovery for Linux desktop users.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Added natural-language date parsing for quick inbox capture so entries like tomorrow resolve while you type.</li>
          <li>Kept desktop sync steadier by preserving queued reruns, restoring Dropbox autosync, and keeping scroll position stable during refreshes.</li>
          <li>Surfaced confirmation, project-drag, calendar, and sync failures more clearly instead of letting them disappear during rerenders.</li>
          <li>Improved self-hosted cloud diagnostics with safer upload blocking and request IDs on 500 responses.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.8.1" date="2026-04-09">
      <url type="details">https://github.com/dongdongbh/Mindwtr/releases/tag/v0.8.1</url>
      <description translate="no">
        <p>Mindwtr 0.8.1 refines desktop planning, inbox processing, and sync reliability for Linux desktop users.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Added adjustable desktop text size controls for more comfortable reading across large and small displays.</li>
          <li>Expanded desktop inbox processing with priority, energy, and assignee fields that respect editor layout settings.</li>
          <li>Improved calendar and Today behavior with clearer selected-day external events and stricter next-action scheduling rules.</li>
          <li>Hardened desktop sync and storage with safer area merge handling and faster task metadata filtering.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.8.0" date="2026-04-05">
      <url type="details">https://github.com/dongdongbh/Mindwtr/releases/tag/v0.8.0</url>
      <description translate="no">
        <p>Mindwtr 0.8.0 improves desktop project planning, sidebar behavior, and storage safety across Linux and other desktop builds.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Added optional project due dates so project planning and review timing are easier to manage.</li>
          <li>Improved the Projects sidebar with single-click selection, a separate archived section, and clearer calendar and review contrast.</li>
          <li>Added configurable inline task editor sections and kept the Obsidian integration settings collapsed until needed.</li>
          <li>Hardened sync and storage with safer pending-write recovery, filtered deleted attachments, clearer keyring fallback warnings, and more consistent search visibility.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.7.9" date="2026-04-01">
      <url type="details">https://github.com/dongdongbh/Mindwtr/releases/tag/v0.7.9</url>
      <description translate="no">
        <p>Mindwtr 0.7.9 improves desktop data portability, Obsidian integration, sync reliability, and day-to-day planning polish.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Added backup restore and Todoist import so desktop users can move task data in and out more easily.</li>
          <li>Expanded the desktop Obsidian integration with TaskNotes support plus live updates and write-back.</li>
          <li>Improved desktop sync behavior for Flatpak, self-hosted, and CloudKit setups, including clearer filter and sync-toggle state.</li>
          <li>Polished planning workflows with better focus filtering, localized delete-undo copy, and safer accessibility fallbacks.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.7.8" date="2026-03-30">
      <url type="details">https://github.com/dongdongbh/Mindwtr/releases/tag/v0.7.8</url>
      <description translate="no">
        <p>Mindwtr 0.7.8 improves desktop project planning, editing polish, audio capture feedback, and Linux packaging details.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Unified project details and notes while collapsing metadata by default for a cleaner planning view.</li>
          <li>Added keyboard shortcut help, autosized task descriptions, and improved project drag targeting.</li>
          <li>Improved audio capture processing feedback and kept task notes hidden until expanded.</li>
          <li>Reorganized sync settings and reduced the Linux app icon footprint for leaner packaging metadata.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.7.7" date="2026-03-26">
      <url type="details">https://github.com/dongdongbh/Mindwtr/releases/tag/v0.7.7</url>
      <description translate="no">
        <p>Mindwtr 0.7.7 focuses on desktop reliability, Linux theme integration, and safer self-hosted release defaults.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Follow system light and dark theme changes more reliably, including AppImage and Linux desktop setups.</li>
          <li>Pause blur-triggered sync while editing tasks and always release offline listeners after sync failures.</li>
          <li>Improve compatibility with blocked filesystem stat calls during Obsidian vault scans.</li>
          <li>Harden cloud and Docker release defaults with explicit auth-token setup, pinned Bun images, and safer packaging checks.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.7.6" date="2026-03-22">
      <url type="details">https://github.com/dongdongbh/Mindwtr/releases/tag/v0.7.6</url>
      <description translate="no">
        <p>Mindwtr 0.7.6 expands desktop workflow customization, adds Manage controls, and tightens sync and Linux packaging behavior.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Added guided and quick inbox processing with more flexible desktop task editor layout settings.</li>
          <li>Added a desktop Manage settings page for areas, contexts, and tags, plus bulk context editing support.</li>
          <li>Improved sync resilience with safer refresh handling, better delete conflict resolution, and attachment presync recovery.</li>
          <li>Polished Linux distribution details with refreshed Flathub assets and safer release tooling updates.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.7.5" date="2026-03-18">
      <url type="details">https://github.com/dongdongbh/Mindwtr/releases/tag/v0.7.5</url>
      <description translate="no">
        <p>Mindwtr 0.7.5 improves desktop deletion flows, settings stability, sync resilience, and Linux packaging polish.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Added confirmation and undo for list deletions, with clearer feedback when restores fail.</li>
          <li>Stabilized the Integrations settings screen and blocked checklist edits on reference-only items.</li>
          <li>Improved sync resilience with safer pending writes, task mutation validation, and better self-write filtering.</li>
          <li>Expanded Linux packaging metadata with AppStream polish and automated Flathub follow-up updates.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.7.4" date="2026-03-16">
      <url type="details">https://github.com/dongdongbh/Mindwtr/releases/tag/v0.7.4</url>
      <description translate="no">
        <p>Mindwtr 0.7.4 adds Apple-platform iCloud sync, a desktop Obsidian workspace, stronger cross-device sync reliability, and faster mobile triage tools.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Added native iCloud sync support on Apple platforms.</li>
          <li>Added Obsidian vault integration on desktop with a dedicated workspace that stays hidden until enabled.</li>
          <li>Improved sync reliability with safer merge handling, bounded cloud requests, and clearer conflict diagnostics.</li>
          <li>Added a global mobile area switcher, time estimate filters, and daily-review focus toggles.</li>
          <li>Improved desktop layouts, sync accessibility, and release tooling for the Node 24 transition.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.7.3" date="2026-03-05">
      <url type="details">https://github.com/dongdongbh/Mindwtr/releases/tag/v0.7.3</url>
      <description translate="no">
        <p>Mindwtr 0.7.3 focused on more consistent sync behavior, safer local persistence, more workflow customization, and better mobile reminder handling.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Unified desktop and mobile sync orchestration to reduce stale queued-sync edge cases.</li>
          <li>Added date and time format overrides and opt-in inbox processing settings on desktop.</li>
          <li>Added a visible mobile sync activity indicator and improved WebDAV rate-limit handling.</li>
          <li>Hardened local storage, search, attachment validation, and self-hosted cloud merge behavior.</li>
          <li>Improved notification reliability, task editing flows, and calendar permission handling.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1"/>
</component>
